const mythologyCategories = [
    {category: 'Greek', point: 100, question: 'Which bird was the symbol of Athena?', answer: 'owl'},
    {category: 'Roman', point: 100, question: 'Who is the Roman god counterpart of Zeus', answer: 'Jupiter'},
    {category: 'Egyptian', point: 100, question: 'What Disney+ series involved Egyptian mythology?', answer: 'Moon Knight'},
    {category: 'Norse', point: 100, question: 'Who was the Norse god of thunder?', answer: 'Thor'},
    {category: 'Japanese', point: 100, question: 'Who is the Japanese goddess of the sun?', answer: 'Amaterasu'},

    {category: 'Greek', point: 200, question: 'Who was the Greek god of wine?', answer: 'Dionysus'},
    {category: 'Roman', point: 200, question: 'The first month of the year is named after which Roman god?', answer: 'Janus'},
    {category: 'Egyptian', point: 200, question: 'What animal symbolizes the goddes Bast?', answer: 'cat'},
    {category: 'Norse', point: 200, question: 'In the latest installment of the game, God of War, Kratos\' son, Loki, is also named what?', answer: 'Atreus'},
    {category: 'Japanese', point: 200, question: 'What is the Japanese word for death god? ', answer: 'Shinigami'},
    
    {category: 'Greek', point: 300, question: 'Who tricked Cronus into swallowing a rock to save Zeus?', answer: 'Rhea'},
    {category: 'Roman', point: 300, question: 'Who is the father of Jupiter?', answer: 'Saturn'},
    {category: 'Egyptian', point: 300, question: 'Who almost killed Ra to get Osiris on the throne?', answer: 'Isis'},
    {category: 'Norse', point: 300, question: 'What is the name of Thor\'s hammer?', answer: 'Mjollnir'},
    {category: 'Japanese', point: 300, question: 'Who is the moon god?', answer: 'Tsukuyomi'},
    
    {category: 'Greek', point: 400, question: 'The mythological beast, Chimera, had a lion\'s head, a goat\'s body, and a what animal\'s tail?', answer: 'snake'},
    {category: 'Roman', point: 400, question: 'What was the name of the great temple in Rome dedicated to the gods?', answer: 'Pantheon'},
    {category: 'Egyptian', point: 400, question: 'Who was the father of the twins, god of air and goddess of moisture, Shu and Tefnut?', answer: 'Atum'},
    {category: 'Norse', point: 400, question: 'What is the name of the monster whom Beowulf defeated?', answer: 'Grendel'},
    {category: 'Japanese', point: 400, question: 'The 8-headed dragon called Yamata no Orochi was slain by which god?', answer: 'Susanoo'},
    
    {category: 'Greek', point: 500, question: 'Pasiphae is the mother of which Greek mythological beast?', answer: 'Minotaur'},
    {category: 'Roman', point: 500, question: 'What was the February 15th festival called, where it involved striking women with goatskins to make them fertile?', answer: 'Lupercalia'},
    {category: 'Egyptian', point: 500, question: 'Which goddess was known as the soul devourer?', answer: 'Ammut'},
    {category: 'Norse', point: 500, question: 'Odin gave the Mead of poetry to scholars obtained from Kvasir\'s what?', answer: 'blood'},
    {category: 'Japanese', point: 500, question: 'Amaterasu, Tsukuyomi, and Susanoo are powers of which Sharingan in Naruto Shipuuden series?', answer: 'Mangekyo'}
]
